Ely Samuel Parker Papers 1794-1946 Mss.497.3.P223
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Linguistic Material, n.d.; 0.25 linear feet (Box 7)
  - Bible. N.T. James. (Box 7)
    Seneca words and phrases, with English translations, in various handwritings, on different sized scraps of paper.
    Seneca words for attributes of God; verso has short Seneca text without English.
    Seneca words for parts of the body, with English translations. 10 p.
  - Address on Mission boarding school, Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    An address in English concerning the necessity of discontinuing a mission boarding school "so that we can send more of our young men to other tribes" [the Flatheads?]. Also part of the same address as delivered by an interpreter in Seneca, with interlinear literal translation into English.
  - Compound forms of gah no go ah, 13 p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Compound forms of gah ni go ah, mind, and wiyu, good.
  - Conjugation of oknegeah, 4p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Conjugation of the Seneca verb, oknegeah, I drink, with English equivalents.
  - Conjugation of yont gen is ah, 3p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Conjugation of the Seneca verb yont gen is ah, without English equivalents.
  - Conjugation of several verbs, Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Conjugation of the verbs arrive, bring, come, give, return and visit, in Seneca with English.
  - Conjugation of take and receive in Seneca, 5p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Conjugation of the verbs take and receive in Seneca with English.
  - Conjugations, 6p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Conjugations in Seneca and English of the verbs see, strike, and think or suppose.
  - [Wright, Asher], Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Deg. 1. He ni ya wah syoh no nah jih... Gowanda, N.Y., H.M. Morgan, printer, n.d. (Scripture tracts in the Seneca language. See Pilling no. 4255.)
  - [Wright, Asher], Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Deg. 5. Gai wa neh ak shah [sin]. (Scripture tract in the Seneca language. Fragment of Pilling no. 4256.)
  - [Wright, Asher], 2p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    A guide to pronounciation of Seneca. A similar but condensed version of this "alphabet" appears on p. [3] and p. 9 respectively of the 1836 and 1842 editions of his "Spelling Book."
  - List of Seneca prefixes and suffixes, Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Lists of Seneca prefixes and suffixes on 12 scraps of paper of various sizes.
  - List of suffixes, Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Lists of "verbal terminations to see if of different conjugations on account of endings." 1 p. in pencil.
  - List of verbs, Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    "List of verbs taken promiscuously, as they occur in books."
  - Miscellaneous grammatical notes, 7p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Miscellaneous notes and questions on Seneca grammatical processes. 5 scraps of paper.
  - Rules and notes on Seneca prefixes and suffixes, Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Rules and notes in English concerning Seneca prefixes and suffixes.
  - [Wright, Asher], 7p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Seneca words of one, two and three syllables, with English translations. Some of these words are among those included in his "Spelling Book" (1842).
  - A table of the ways of representing the various relations which in other languages are represented by prepositions, 5p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
  - Seneca word lists, 33p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Word lists in Seneca, for the most part with English translations, arranged alphabetically by initial letters as follows: De, Deh, Ga, Go, loose sheets.
  - Seneca word lists, ca.197p.; Wright, Asher (Box 7)
    Word lists in Seneca, without English translations, arranged alphabetically by initial letters only, as follows: A, D, E, G, H, J, K, O, S, T, W and Y. A notebook, 6.5 Ö 8 inches.
  - Miscellaneous, Wright, Laura M. (Box 7)
    Brief specimen of her handwriting, written in Seneca.
    Word list in English, without translation; each entry is assigned a number from 1 to 359.
  - Phonetic symbols and Seneca syllables, [Young, James]? (Box 7)
    Phonetic symbols and Seneca syllables. 1 double and 3 single sheets.
  - Seneca word lists, Parker, Fred Ely (Box 7)
    Word lists in Seneca, without English translations, arranged alphabetically [for Asher Wright?] as follows:
    - A: 514 words
    - C: 32 words
    - D: 134 words
    - E: 16 words
    - G: 132 words
    - H: 1,182 words
    - J: 50 words
    - K: 9 words
    - N: 1,420 words
    - O: 138 words
    - S: 338 words
    - T: 13 words
    - W: 167 words
    - Y: 75 words